<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Geekery &#8211; Creeva&#039;s World 3.0</title>
	<atom:link href="https://creeva.com/index.php/category/geekery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://creeva.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Playstation 4 &#8211; Remote Play And You</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2017/03/09/playstation-4-remote-play-and-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 18:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=95390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This was originally written for Duesr.com Like Legion, this is another one where I just might be late to the party. I don&#8217;t think so though. I think is something that people are not really &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ps4-logo-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-95354" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ps4-logo-1-1.jpg" alt="" width="747" height="309" /></a></p>
<p><em>This was originally written for Duesr.com</em></p>
<p>Like <a href="http://duesr.com/index.php/2017/03/09/want-fantastic-comic-book-tv-watch-legion-fx/">Legion</a>, this is another one where I just might be late to the party. I don&#8217;t think so though. I think is something that people are not really aware of. The most important thing about this feature that you likely aren&#8217;t using is that it is free. Free as in beer and not free as in speech. You do have to own the necessary components, but most people reading this site that are in the Playstation camp likely already have everything they need.</p>
<p>So let&#8217;s go over it to catch everyone up with what it is and why it is useful.</p>
<h2>What is Remote Play</h2>
<p>Remote Play allows you to stream games from the Playstation 4 to a compatible device. Don&#8217;t have a Playstation 4 to take with you on the road? Well if you have a laptop and a controller, you are good to go.</p>
<p>For more advanced geeks, think of it as Remote Desktop or VNC. The difference is that the streaming is good enough to handle videos. The Playstation Now service currently allows you to stream PS3 games to your PS4 console. This is just a private version of that service.</p>
<p>Remote Play works across a local network or across the Internet. The limiting factor is only the bandwidth available. I&#8217;ve had it work in hotels to home Internet &#8211; but your mileage may vary.</p>
<h2>What Supports Remote Play</h2>
<p>Primarily Remote Play supports Windows and MacOs. There is also the Sony Experia cell phone, the Playstation TV, and the Vita that supported this functionality. I have seen discussion that the Vita and Playstation TV support is being dropped. This is personally annoying since I am one of the few people who own a Playstation TV device.</p>
<h2>Do I Really Need a Playstation 4 Then?</h2>
<p>Remote Play performs a connection back to your personal Playstation 4. The service will not work in any other way. Simply put, you are required to own a Playstation 4.</p>
<h2>What Are The Limitations?</h2>
<p>The biggest limitation I have found is this only works in a single user mode. That means if my wife is watching Netflix on the Playstation 4 in the living room, I can&#8217;t stream a game to my office. Only a single person can access a Playstation 4 (locally or remotely) at a time. If you live in a household like mine where the Playstation 4 is the main media backend on the TV, you are stuck until it is free. On the plus side, if this is a service you start using all the time, you have an excuse to buy an extra one to stick in a closet or basement attached to your network.</p>
<p>If you feel even more at hacking away at new features &#8211; these can also be done with the Playstation 3. The Playstation 3 supported Remote Play for PSP and Vita devices. By reverse engineering the protocol, some enterprising developers made a version for PS3 to Windows/Mac clients. You can read more about that here.</p>
<p>Have any of you ever actually done Remote Play, or am I the only one?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Use Two Sets of Bluetooth Headphones at the Same Time with OSX/MacOs</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2017/03/05/how-to-use-two-sets-of-bluetooth-headphones-at-the-same-time-with-osxmacos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 18:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=95271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two nights ago my wife and were in the hotel sharing a room with my son. The last time this happened my son stayed up most the night since my wife and I couldn&#8217;t fall &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-95272" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-300x197.png" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-300x197.png 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1.png 660w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-95272" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-300x197.png" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1-300x197.png 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/multi-1.png 660w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>Two nights ago my wife and were in the hotel sharing a room with my son. The last time this happened my son stayed up most the night since my wife and I couldn&#8217;t fall asleep early. So this time we both brought bluetooth headphones and were going to watch Netflix. Since my son was on the sofa bed, we could position the laptop to not keep him awake. We thought this was going to be an easy exercise, but it was harder than we thought. After 30-40 minutes we had the whole thing working. I thought I would write it up so no one else had to go through this.</p>
<p>Most the discussions when you search for this in Google are on message boards with multiple links sending you somewhere else. Here are the steps that are required.</p>
<ol>
<li> Connect all your bluetooth head phones to your Mac</li>
<li>Go to Applications &gt; Utilities</li>
<li>Open &#8220;Audio Midi Setup&#8221;</li>
<li>In the plus sign at the bottom left, click and select Multi-Output Device</li>
<li>Rename your Multi-Output Device to something memorable</li>
<li>In the Windows select both sets of your Bluetooth headphones (if they have microphones they will show up twice, Microphones have 1 channel, Headphones/Speakers have 2).</li>
</ol>
<p>Now you have everything configured you can right click your new multi-output device and select &#8220;use this device for sound output&#8221;. For immediate concern you should be all set.</p>
<p>If this is something that is going to be in regular use, I recommend a couple other things. The first is to have your volume control show up on the menu bar. To to do this</p>
<ol>
<li>Open System Preferences</li>
<li>Click on Sound</li>
<li>Under Output Devices you can see &#8220;Show Volume on the Menu Bar&#8221; at the bottom &#8211; enable this.</li>
</ol>
<p>On this screen you can also control different outputs switching between internal speakers and your new multi-output device. However, once you have the volume control in the Menu Bar &#8211; you can switch between different outputs quickly. They will show up underneath the volume control when you click the speaker. Airplay and other output devices will show up as selections.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m just hoping for someone else this becomes a 5 minute fix instead of spending na hour clicking different links.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Setting up a Faux Landline So My Son Can Get Calls</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2016/04/21/setting-up-a-faux-landline-so-my-son-can-get-calls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 15:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=95001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; We have reached that dreaded age that every parent must face. The one where your child wants to be able to make their own phone calls and receive calls from friends. My child is &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-95030" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-1024x714.jpg" alt="telephone-1055044_1920" width="640" height="446" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-1024x714.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-300x209.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-768x536.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1-1536x1071.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/telephone-1055044_1920-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We have reached that dreaded age that every parent must face. The one where your child wants to be able to make their own phone calls and receive calls from friends. My child is young enough that we thought we had at least a couple more years before this became a thing. We were wrong though. This started last year and I got a half-baked solution working. It was a bit too complex for him (my wife would say most thing I architect are a bit too complex). In fairness it wasn&#8217;t dumb easy, but he had it. The problem was it didn&#8217;t work reliably. It used third party solutions and was ugly. However it did route through a google voice number tied to my son&#8217;s email account.</p>
<p>As an aside, my son doesn&#8217;t have an email account exactly. It&#8217;s an email address we registered when he was born. It was configured as a catch all address for him to use as an identity. It is controlled by my wife and myself, my son has never logged into it. Any web services that could be tied to him we use as his proxy. All email is forwarded to both wife and myself in our personal email addresses. This is to make sure there is never anything inappropriate sent to that account. One day we will turn it over to him, but not anytime soon. Having a Google Voice just for him tied to this account was something that just made sense.</p>
<p>Since my original solution did not work, overtime the Google Voice number was surrendered due to inactivity. This was fine since he did not have it memorized and in theory we could get him a new one at a later date. However, this wasn&#8217;t as easy it would seem &#8211; but more on that later. Over the last few months my son was more adamant about people being able to call. I use my phone for personal and business use all hours of the day. My wife uses hers for various reasons. We did not want to hand out our numbers to everyone to get calls from other kids at any given time. This left my son without an option.</p>
<p>We did have a landline, but we don&#8217;t have a phone plugged into it. We have it down to the bare minimum of services so it costs per minute for any call. The only reason we still have it is that it saves us a couple dollars a month on our total DSL bill. I had nightmares of my son starting to use the phone and running up large bills just talking to grandma. To elevate the service to not be per minute would cost me about $20.00 a month or $240.00 a year. That did not quite make me happy either. It would get worse also. If he called family, all of them are long distance. So I would have to pay long distance fees on top of the other costs. I haven&#8217;t paid long distance fees in years thanks to the cell phone. We had to look for other solutions.</p>
<p>Of course the discussion of &#8220;maybe he should get a cell phone&#8221; came up. I couldn&#8217;t justify that cost either. Especially since my wife and I are grandfathered into unlimited data plans and there would no way to get him on one. With his current iPad usage I can only imagine the eventual data overages because he was streaming video from the Reading Rainbow app. This was a no go either just for cost and logistical training I would have to try to teach a boy who thinks things just work and has no concept of data.</p>
<p>Back to the Google Voice solution. A month ago a friend talked to me about this problem. He used an Obi202 which routed through Google Voice. This meant unless he was making international calls that all calls were free. All he had to do was purchase the unit itself. It used a wired ethernet connection, but for $20.00 more he got a wifi adapter that worked with it. This was going to be something to look into. I put this in the back of my mind and eventually after again hearing that my son wanted to make his own calls, I ordered it last week. It was 49.99 with free shipping so it would pay for itself in 3 months over changing the phone service.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/33-617-008-TS-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-95034" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/33-617-008-TS-1-1.jpg" alt="33-617-008-TS" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>The device came and I let it sit for a few days. I eventually got around to try and it work on Friday night. The first thing was getting my son a Google Voice number again. You would think would be a straight forward proposition, it was not. I hooked up a phone to my home phone line and verified it with Google Voice. I then browsed the phone numbers. I found one I thought looked good and selected it. Once I clicked the button, I received the message that would be the bane of my evening &#8220;There was an error with your request. Please try again.&#8221; I tried again. It was the same result. The service might be busy so I waited awhile and tried again. I still wasn&#8217;t having any luck. Then I started searching online.</p>
<p>One of the things that came up was the fact if a phone had been used by Google Voice before it couldn&#8217;t be activated in a different account. I have two google voice accounts and this number wasn&#8217;t bound to anything. Just in case though, I would need a new number. Since our cell phones were already activated to our respective accounts I could not use that. I downloaded an app for my phone that allowed you to generate burner numbers. These temporary numbers would work for a set amount of time and then disappear. I paid $1.99 to get a number that would work for 14 days. I received the number and verified Google Voice, then chose a new number to add. The problem was I received the same error message.</p>
<p>It seems that something can trigger on Google&#8217;s backend that can block the addition or reactivation of a Google Voice account. There was a thread where tehy could reset an account, but they put a notice that they no longer did that. Even if I could move forward on that, it would take days to resolve. I was impatient and there has never been a thing like a Google customer support line. I was on my own and I was going to brute force this scenario.</p>
<p>I removed all phones from my son&#8217;s Google Voice account. I then opened a new Gmail account. Using this account I forwarded all email messages to my son&#8217;s account &#8211; which in theory should have forwarded it to myself and my wife. Then I went to Google Voice and prepared for the worst. I signed up for the account and verified the number to the burner number I got. Then I went to choose a new number &#8211; and this time it worked. I then went and configured the Obi device. I called the number from my cell phone and everything worked. I then set the burner phone number to never ring and tested it again. Everything was still working as expected. All text messages, voicemails, and missed call notifications would be forwarded to this email address. Everything should be right.</p>
<p>Now it was time to test. I sent a text message to the new number. It came through to the new email address, but not his existing one. A Gmail filter later and another test it was getting to his real email address. It seems Gmail doesn&#8217;t like forwarding messages it already forwarded on another account. This is likely to prevent an accidental loop where email just keeps flowing constantly until an email box is full. Since there are different alerts depending on missed calls, text messages, and voicemails &#8211; I had to configure a few filters that forwarded these messages to my son&#8217;s account, my wife&#8217;s account, and my own. This keeps with the whole vigilant on what is going on in your child&#8217;s life.</p>
<p>The phone he is using is a standard home cordless phone. So he won&#8217;t be doing text messaging anytime soon. However, he loves it as is. His nickname is even part of the phone number (yes I&#8217;m that much of a geek). The last few days as I have been on the road we have been talking on his phone. This gives him just a bit more freedom than he has had &#8211; since in theory he can have people call him. Whenever he does get a cell phone, he can configure the service for that and keep the same number through however many iterations of phones he goes through in his life. My wife and I will answer the phone first until he learns about wrong numbers and such. Still it is something more in this world he has for himself.</p>
<p>As for the Obi box. If there are no issues in the next few months I plan on purchasing 1-2 more of them. Then my wife will be able to use her old rotary phone to receive calls. I doubt Google Voice supports pulse dialing, so likely it won&#8217;t work for outbound. Just the nostalgia though of having the ability to answer a rotary phone again would be neat. I plan on getting something more comfortable than an iPhone when I have long conference calls. So this would be the reason I would get one for myself. Everything old is new again. Everything is working. It was a frustrating adventure. All my son wanted was to receive calls and make them &#8211; and it turned into this.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Real Security Issue With The Cloud and the IoT &#8211; Loss of Access</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2016/04/11/the-real-security-issue-with-the-cloud-and-the-iot-loss-of-access/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 20:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; The most important thing for anyone in IT is control over your assets and investments. The loss of control can cause you to be vulnerable and helpless even if what you have lost is &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94971" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94971" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="broken-window-960188_1280" width="640" height="426" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/broken-window-960188_1280-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The most important thing for anyone in IT is control over your assets and investments. The loss of control can cause you to be vulnerable and helpless even if what you have lost is menial. In the modern corporate world businesses are outsourcing projects and infrastructure at an accelerated rate. This means you have to rely on the companies that you have invested time and effort in. If these companies suddenly disappear large investments might be needed to re-architect a solution. I&#8217;m sure some of you reading this have had to deal with that exact situation.</p>
<p>While do you have corporate disaster recovery or contingency plans to deal with this at work, what do you do when it happens at home? Over the last decade as we have become accustomed to the internet age, we are familiar with web apps or social networks that are hot one day, yet disappear the next. This is the nature of business. We then move onto the next site, re-upload our images, and reconnect with our contacts. It&#8217;s annoying, yet a fact that we deal with. What we have lost is time and possibly some connections.</p>
<p>In the age of cloud connected Internet of Things devices (IoT) this access changes dramatically in the inconvenience. At home we are investing in smart devices at an increasing rate. If we take out devices we take for granted such as phones, computers, and tablets the items around my house that have an investment in intelligence is quite large. Just off the top of my head I use a Wink hub to control lighting for almost all the bulbs inside and outside of my house, a Nest thermostat, a generic Z-Wave thermostat, multi-room audio, many game consoles, and streaming devices. My house even has smoke detectors on every floor that alerts me if there is an issue. This has actually worked by sending me a phone alert when my dehumidifier bit the dust in a puff of smoke in the basement.</p>
<p>I have heavily invested in different IoT devices that have made my life easier by giving me functionality and scheduling to live without thinking about turning on the outside lights at night. Being a geek I also enjoy the sheer communication and possibilities that these devices give me. Last year however Wink sent out a bad update for their hub. You could send in your device for replacement &#8211; or eventually if you were tech inclined enough to make a DNS record on your LAN &#8211; a way to reflash the firmware. This wasn&#8217;t really to much of an inconvenience since it was corrected. I had to use the light switch instead of controlling the bulbs from my phone. Life went on and everything was corrected. What if it hadn&#8217;t though?</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94974" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94974" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-1024x204.jpg" alt="revolv" width="640" height="128" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-1024x204.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-300x60.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-768x153.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1-1536x306.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/revolv-1.jpg 1757w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>Revolv is an IoT company that makes a competing device to the Wink hub. It was recently announced that they were ending service on May 15th. Revolv has a similar issue to Wink &#8211; it relies on cloud components to allow it to work. This is my largest complaint about Wink overall. If the web service goes down, your devices that you have invested in have stopped working. This means that any lights that were controlled by your Revolv hub will stop functioning as smart devices. Any home automation such as blinds or controlling power to shut off at night for the coffee maker that you route through the hub will also cease.</p>
<p>If you are used to your lights coming on and your door automatically unlocking when you are on the porch, wouldn&#8217;t you feel at least a tinge of helplessness? This is sure to happen to some people that have invested in Revolv as their home infrastructure. Not everyone reads alerts and messages from companies &#8211; so a percentage won&#8217;t know about this until it breaks. The end-users don&#8217;t really have a recourse either. In the corporate environment you have contracts that protect you from this process for your corporate data. However, for consumer devices most of these services are free and there is no contract between the end-user and the corporation that allows them any insurance or compensation. Depending on the infrastructure they purchased into &#8211; they might be out hundreds if not thousands of dollars. The devices might become dumb or stop working all together if the technology is proprietary.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94975" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94975" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-1024x724.jpg" alt="fear-441402_1920" width="640" height="453" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-1024x724.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-300x212.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-768x543.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1-1536x1086.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/fear-441402_1920-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>Of course your first claim on purchasing technology such as this is buyer beware. Trust in the company you are investing your devices with. You might pay more to be with a company who has a brand you trust &#8211; but you expect them to be around longer. Personally I had not heard of Revolv until this story started passing around. However, even you haven&#8217;t heard of them doesn&#8217;t mean they are not owned by a company you trust. Two years ago Revolv was purchased by Nest. This was after Nest was already owned by Google. Currently Revolv, Nest, and Google are subsidiaries of Alphabet &#8211; one of the most valuable companies in the world.</p>
<p>As companies are expanding the use of consumer devices with a corporate setting they need to take into account scenarios like this. If Revolv uses open technologies, most users and companies that were relying on the service should be able to recover. It will take time to reconfigure everything, personally if this Wink that discontinuing service it would likely take me a few hours just to re-sync my light bulbs to a new device or service. It also likely won&#8217;t be a company with the financial backing that Revolv had behind it.</p>
<p><em>About the Author</em></p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94976" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-94976" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA-1-150x150.jpg" alt="AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA" width="150" height="150" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA-1-300x300.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/AAEAAQAAAAAAAAQNAAAAJDZiMDNiZWY0LWMyNWQtNGNmMy1hZDkyLWU0MTJkMjRkYTMwZA-1.jpg 337w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
<p><em>Brent M. Gueth is a Senior Security Consultant with Conventus specializing in Symantec Endpoint Protection and Symantec Data Center Security. He has worked in the IT Security field for over a decade including positions with Symantec and NASA. He has consulted for many Fortune 500 companies and assisted them with their security needs. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rental Car Reviews &#8211; Ford Focus SE Hatchback</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2016/04/09/rental-car-reviews-ford-focus-se-hatchback/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rental car reviews used to be something I wrote up on Facebook. &#160; Just something to share between friends. &#160;I travel at least a week a month so I normally have an overview of some &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94952" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94952" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="2016-03-29 20.53.23" width="640" height="480" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-29-20.53.23-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>Rental car reviews used to be something I wrote up on Facebook. &nbsp; Just something to share between friends. &nbsp;I travel at least a week a month so I normally have an overview of some type of car. &nbsp; I spend four days driving it and get an overview of how the car performs and feels. &nbsp; I&#8217;ve decided to move these reviews over to my personal blog for better showing any images I may have, and let&#8217;s be fair, the interface to writing on WordPress is so much better than the writing interface used by Facebook.</p>
<p>During the last week of March I drove a Ford Focus Hatchback. &nbsp; The last time I was in one of these was back in 2002. &nbsp; I wasn&#8217;t a fan then, and this current trip didn&#8217;t convince i need to trade in for one today. &nbsp;In all fairness though, I&#8217;m a bit biased. &nbsp; I&#8217;m not a Ford fan at all. &nbsp; This comes from growing up in a town where everyone worked for Ford. &nbsp; Since everyone worked at Ford (except my family), everyone drove a Ford. &nbsp;I was burnt out even before I was a driver. &nbsp;Since becoming a driver, my impression hasn&#8217;t been turned around.</p>
<p>The Ford Focus they gave me was the five door hatchback. &nbsp; It has the problems that I have with most small cars, it seems jittery. &nbsp;After getting accustomed to either large cars or sports cars &#8211; compact cars seem a bit unsure of themselves. &nbsp; I&#8217;ve owned compact cars &#8211; so this is par for the course. &nbsp; While I don&#8217;t like, &nbsp;have owned them. &nbsp; So if this is your preference, it is par for the course.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94953" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94953" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="2016-03-30 12.26.01" width="640" height="480" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.01-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>During my driving (almost all in-town and rare highway) I was getting about 31 MPG. &nbsp; My normal car (Dodge Charger AWD V8) get&#8217;s about 22 MPG in the same environment. &nbsp; My 2004 Miata was still getting 30MPG with over 100k on the odometer. &nbsp; I honestly was expecting to get closer to 38-40MPG. &nbsp; This is part of the problem when people consider small cars. &nbsp; Since smaller car rev higher &#8211; those higher RPMs use more gas. &nbsp; Now at cruising speed they will use less gas. &nbsp;However if the car is underpowered using the gas pedal to get up to speed will use more gas than maybe a car with a larger engine. &nbsp; Beyond tat initial acceleration a small engine will always use less gas if it is properly sized for the car. &nbsp;The one example I can turn to is the V6 2005 Grand Cherokee. &nbsp; This engine configuration actually get&#8217;s 2MPG less than the V8 configuration.<br />
<a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94959" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94959" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="2016-03-30 12.26.21" width="640" height="480" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.21-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>While it is a compact car the space in the rear seat is terrible. &nbsp; When i was growing up my family owned a few small cars. &nbsp;The back seat never seemed squished when I was growing up. &nbsp; However, this focus had the leg room in the back that would rival a third gen Camaro in the game who has the least amount of space. &nbsp; If you were thinking about getting one for a family, definitely pay attention to this.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-94956" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94956" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="2016-03-30 12.26.09" width="640" height="480" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-768x576.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/2016-03-30-12.26.09-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>My largest complaint though about the car is the gear shifter visual location. &nbsp; In the picture above the shifter looks like it is in Neutral. &nbsp; However, it is actually in Drive. &nbsp;The worst part about this (even though the picture washes out the D and the L) is that there is a Low&nbsp;below Drive. &nbsp; When I first pulled out the rental car location it was driving me nuts how high the engine was revving. &nbsp; This is when I discovered that the shifter looks to be in a higher position than it actually is. &nbsp; It could be the leather boot around it that obscures it&#8217;s actual position.</p>
<p>Overall it&#8217;s a normal point A to point B car. &nbsp;Back in my very early twenties, that&#8217;s what I thought a car was for. &nbsp;I was a point A to B person for vehicles. &nbsp; Now they are extension of myself in so many ways. &nbsp; I appreciate this car what it is, a standard car without frills. &nbsp; It&#8217;s one of the first rental cars I&#8217;ve had where you can&#8217;t disable traction control (most the time you won&#8217;t see a difference in the compact whether that&#8217;s on or off). &nbsp;I did chirp the tires once getting out of someone&#8217;s way. &nbsp; Beyond that it was predictable and reliable without trying to overcompensate in anyway. &nbsp; That has it&#8217;s good and bad depending on what type of driver you are.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Loss of Last.fm to IFTTT and How Pinboard Exposed the Real Reasons</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2016/03/31/the-loss-of-last-fm-to-ifttt-and-how-pinboard-exposed-the-real-reasons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; On March 9th I received the following email from IFTTT: Hello, We have been busy bringing improvements to the IFTTT platform. Because of these technical updates, some Channels will no longer be supported. On March &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/last-fm-logo-1-1.png" rel="attachment wp-att-94927" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-94927" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/last-fm-logo-1-300x115.png" alt="last-fm-logo" width="300" height="115" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/last-fm-logo-1-300x115.png 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/last-fm-logo-1.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On March 9th I received the following email from <a href="http://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hello,</p>
<p>We have been busy bringing improvements to the IFTTT platform. Because of these technical updates, some Channels will no longer be supported.</p>
<p>On March 23rd, the following Channels and their Recipes will be removed from IFTTT: App.net, BuzzFeed, Campfire, Diigo, Etsy, ffffound, Last.fm, Readability, Yahoo Fantasy Sports, and Yammer.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, we’ve added over 30 Channels and encourage you come check out what’s new and noteworthy on IFTTT!</p>
<p>—The IFTTT Team</p></blockquote>
<p>I immediately hit <a href="http://reddit.com/">Reddit</a> and looked at the IFTTT and <a href="http://last.fm.com/" class="broken_link">Last.FM</a> subreddits to see if there was any more information on the issue. I wanted to see what other thoughts there were on the issue and if there were any hacks or work around to keep this going. My first thought was that I would use the RSS feeds from last.fm to keep the data flowing. However, what I found out is that last.fm has gone under a major revamp in the last year. While this revamp allowed for new uses via API&#8217;s &#8211; it also broke the RSS feeds the site offered. There was no cure in sight.</p>
<p>I looked into the API&#8217;s that last.fm did offer and tried to come up with a solution. The best options I had at that time was to roll something of my own sing existing scripts that other people had offered. However, I didn&#8217;t want to overload my hosting provider and I didn&#8217;t want something that required me to make sure my system was always running and the script going. This was one of those nice to have things, but not enough dire to completely freak out over.</p>
<p>For some idea of what I was using this integration for, let me list a few of the last.fm recipes I used to have. My last played song would show up as currently playing on my twitter account. When I played a song it would match up to Google Calendar and record that as an event. It would email me the songs as they were recorded (filtered, but searchable since I use Gmail as a thought/experience database). Finally it would save all the songs in a text file &#8211; bypassing the need to worry about an export of the data from last.fm. This is data I generated and I like being in control/aware of it. Some people might think it is silly &#8211; but IFTTT gave me that power.</p>
<p>This has been something I&#8217;ve been looking at for a few weeks. Today I&#8217;m looking at some tools that allow me to post songs automatically from last.fm to twitter, tumblr, etc. and using that as the bridge to get back the functionality that I have lost. It&#8217;s not a great solution since there will be more moving parts &#8211; but it might make this workable. If I figure out something that looks decent enough, I will do a write-up. I know there are quite a few last.fm fans &#8211; since my blog gets hit daily for my article on <a href="https://creeva.com/2012/03/08/i-have-successfully-merged-last-fm-accounts-here-is-a-howto/" class="broken_link">how to migrate last.fm accounts</a>.</p>
<p>How did this happen though? What was IFTTT changing that caused this to break? The first thing that came to mind was the revamp that last.fm performed. This API migration was finished though. IFTTT recipes were working and there were no new architectural announcements by last.fm. There was a chance that last.fm had plans that weren&#8217;t public &#8211; but IFTTT was the one stating they were doing a revamp. Things didn&#8217;t add up completely.</p>
<p>On Tuesday though the pieces started falling into place. The CEO of <a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2016/03/my_heroic_and_lazy_stand_against_ifttt/">Pinboard wrote up a blog post</a> (<a href="https://blog.pinboard.in/2016/03/my_heroic_and_lazy_stand_against_ifttt/">click here</a>) explaining what he went through with IFTTT. In the article he explains that IFTTT was demanding that he re-architect his site to work with IFTTT. IFTTT was expecting special access and an agreement contract where the data passing through the rules would become property of IFTTT. Since IFTT is seen as a conduit service (something that connects services together) it was always in the position of making it&#8217;s service working with the API&#8217;s of others. However, in recent years IFTTT has gained more power and it seems they are trying to make connect sites bend to their wills. I think this will backfire on IFTTT in the long run. I just hope it won&#8217;t gut the service. This may be their jump the shark moment.</p>
<p>Thinking about it though &#8211; you know Twitter and Facebook are not signing the agreements that were sent to Pinboard. The design team at IFTTT must be taking advantage of the little guy in this regard. They have services such as Twitter and Facebook that they must work with to stay relevant. In this arena they have to be bowing to the wills and limited access that these services provide to outside individuals via the API. However, for smaller sites it seems that they tried to force their hand. While Last.fm and some of the sites are smaller &#8211; I&#8217;m kind of surprised that Etsy was on the list. Obviously they must not have caved to the new TOS contract IFTTT sent over, but at the same time they are not large enough to have the must have power that Facebook and Twitter wield.</p>
<p>Here is to hoping that I can hack something together to bring this functionality back for myself.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get 1 Terabyte of Google Storage Space By Becoming a Local Guide</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2015/11/19/get-1-terabyte-of-google-storage-space-by-becoming-a-local-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 19:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is a Local Guide I know reading the headline, some of you are wondering what the heck is a Google Local Guide? This is actually a service that has existed for awhile in Google. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94835" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-1024x575.jpg" alt="maxresdefault" width="640" height="359" srcset="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-300x168.jpg 300w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-768x431.jpg 768w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1-1536x863.jpg 1536w, https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/maxresdefault-1.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>What is a Local Guide</strong></p>
<p>I know reading the headline, some of you are wondering what the heck is a <a href="https://www.google.com/local/guides/">Google Local Guide</a>? This is actually a service that has existed for awhile in Google. It&#8217;s a competitive service to <a href="http://yelp.com/">Yelp</a>. It&#8217;s designed to offer images and reviews of restaurants, businesses, and places. In Google&#8217;s words:</p>
<blockquote><p>Share your world on Google Maps. Local Guides is a global community of explorers sharing their discoveries on Google Maps. Help others find the best spots in town, make new friends, and unlock exclusive benefits along the way.</p></blockquote>
<p><center><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nqN5YD0N2dM?rel=0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></center><br />
<strong>Local Guide Rewards</strong></p>
<p>This last week <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/lianeyvkoff/2015/11/16/google-gamifies-local-guides-to-boost-maps/">Google announced new benefits to becoming a member of their Local Guides</a>. They have placed in guide levels. I&#8217;ll be honest, these levels might have been in place previously. I hadn&#8217;t heard of the service until this week. However, the rewards are new. The rewards are based on your level tiers.</p>
<ul>
<li>Level 1 &#8211; (0 &#8211; 4 points) allows users to enter exclusive contests in select countries</li>
<li>Level 2 &#8211; (5 &#8211; 49 points) provides early access to new Google products and features.</li>
<li>Level 3 &#8211; (50 &#8211; 199 points) allows a user to show up in the Google Maps app with an official Local Guides badge.</li>
<li>Level 4 &#8211; (200 &#8211; 499 points) offers a free 1 TB upgrade of the user&#8217;s Drive storage.</li>
<li>Level 5 &#8211; (500+ points) allows reviewers to become eligible to apply to attend the company&#8217;s inaugural summit in 2016. (Details will be released next year.)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How To Earn Local Guide Points</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://support.google.com/local-guides/answer/6225851?hl=en">Google wrote up a help page about how to earn points</a>. I&#8217;ll give you the quick rundown. The first thing you need to do is look up the business in Google Maps. From there you can rate and review a restaurant. This gives you 1 point. If you are on a mobile app it will ask you additional questions such as &#8220;Do They Offer Take Out&#8221; or &#8220;Is This Place Cash Only&#8221;. This takes about 10 seconds and gives you a second point. If you add a picture, that gains you a point. If you correct details such as hours &#8211; that gives you a point.</p>
<p>You can take a picture of a business without rating it. You can not do the questions without first providing a rating.</p>
<p><strong>Are Points Only Gained From Places I&#8217;m Local To?</strong></p>
<p>One of the things they ask you when you first sign up is they ask for your zip code. I was curious if it would allow me to review places a few states away (currently I&#8217;m on travel this week). It does and those points forward towards your count. Anywhere you know well enough to review you can go back and place in the review. In theory you could put in places you haven&#8217;t been &#8211; but be fair and make the system work accurately.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>What Is The Downside?</strong></p>
<p>All images and reviews you submit are available for public view. The images do show up on your Google Plus page as public, but you can modify your security to hide this tab. This may or may not be a security concern for you. After you reach the top level you are shooting for you can then leave the local guide program. At this point you are supposed to be able to remove all of your information. How true this is, I can&#8217;t answer. I did want to point out the issue though. Google also hasn&#8217;t stated if you will lose the terabyte space increase if you leave the program. To that end, they have stated if this will be a yearly item you will need to achieve to maintain it or if it&#8217;s a one time for life item. These are some unanswered questions that you may want to consider.</p>
<p><strong>Verifying Your Points</strong></p>
<p>To verify how many points you have earned, you need to use the mobile app. I haven&#8217;t seen any quick method to see this on the standard website. In the app click the three lines next to the search bar. This will open a side screen that let&#8217;s you select your contributions. At the top will be your level and how many points you have. You can click the points bar and it will break down where you received points from (reviews, photos, answers, added places, and edited places). At the bottom you have a todo section (mine is blank) this recommends places for you to try out. There are two more tabs on the bottom you can switch to. The first is the Reviews tab, this lists all the reviews you have added to the program. The second is the Photos tab which shows all the photos you have contributed and lists have many people have seen them.</p>
<p>By the end of this week I should already be level 5. I&#8217;ve been reviewing and uploading pictures in my spare time. The points rack up quickly. The only annoyance is that it takes about a day to post, so you can&#8217;t watch the points go up automatically as you do things. This is interesting for all those who are always wanting more cloud space. It also helps the community by improving search results down to a local level.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Losing Contacts &#8211; Consolidate on Google Contacts</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2015/11/14/stop-losing-contacts-consolidate-on-google-contacts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 19:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; When I wrote up the piece on backing up your photos I mentioned how this is a regular complaint on Facebook. The other thing that I don&#8217;t understand in this era is losing contacts. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/logo6w-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-94821" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/logo6w-1-1.png" alt="logo6w" width="538" height="190" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When I wrote up the piece on <a href="https://creeva.com/2015/11/05/backing-up-all-of-your-pictures-in-2015-how-i-do-it/" class="broken_link">backing up your photos</a> I mentioned how this is a regular complaint on Facebook. The other thing that I don&#8217;t understand in this era is losing contacts. Currently in my cleaned and trimmed address book I have over 2600 contacts. At my high point I had over 4000, until I standardized, cleaned up, and backed up everything. I took the pain so you don&#8217;t have to. This article should give you a shortcut for what took me many years to learn.</p>
<p>Android has the feature to directly integrate with <a href="https://contacts.google.com/">Google Contacts</a>. The people that lose contacts at that platform just must have set their contacts to only be stored locally. The first step for Android folks is to make sure this integration is configured before going forward in this article on consolidating your contacts across platforms.</p>
<p>If you are using IOS &#8211; <a href="https://support.google.com/mail/answer/2753077?hl=en">Google created this help document on getting Google Integration on your device</a>. This integration configures syncing of <a href="https://gmail.com/">Gmail</a>, <a href="https://calendar.google.com/">Google Calendar</a>, and Google Contacts. If you weren&#8217;t using Google before, the contact use case might be enough of a reason to join now. I&#8217;ve standardized on Gmail and Google Calendar for those types of services and all my data is synced across my laptops and mobile devices.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Getting Contacts From Other Services</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/EcWNlRB9-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-94822" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/EcWNlRB9-1-1.png" alt="EcWNlRB9" width="400" height="400" /></a>Google isn&#8217;t the only place you have contacts. This is especially true if you are not a heavy Gmail user. For the other Web/Mobile services you use, you will want those contacts included into your address book. <a href="https://app.fullcontact.com/" class="broken_link">Full Contact</a> is the primary method you are going to use to sync and add these contacts from other services.</p>
<p>Full contact supports the following web services Google Contacts, LinkedIn (more on this in a second), Twitter, Facebook, Foursquare, Instagram, iCloud, Angel list, and Xing. The last three services I don&#8217;t use at all, so I haven&#8217;t configured them. If you want to use iCloud you can skip over Google Contacts completely (I think), but it will make cleanup much more painful in the long run. I mentioned that it supports LinkedIn, but this functionality is not native. It requires you export a file from the LinkedIn service and then import it in manually. So LinkedIn connections are going to be an ongoing task depending on how often you add in new connections.</p>
<p>Something you are going to have to consider once you start using Full Contact is how you interact with these different services and how you want the contacts from those services included into your address book. For each service there are two options. The first option is to add contacts to your address book. Whenever you add a new connection on any of these services, a new contact will be created in your address book (we will get to handle duplicates later). The other option is to update information from existing contacts with the information from these other services. Google and iCloud (I believe) offer a full sync option on top of the two.</p>
<p>The problem I&#8217;ve run across is that some of this contact information is useless. For example if you have an Instagram contact that doesn&#8217;t have an email or phone number, that isn&#8217;t very useful to you. I have my services configured in the following manner:</p>
<ul>
<li>Google Contacts &#8211; Sync</li>
<li>Linkedin &#8211; Add Contacts</li>
<li>Facebook &#8211; Add Contacts</li>
<li>Twitter &#8211; Update Contacts</li>
<li>Foursquare &#8211; Update Contacts</li>
<li>Instagram &#8211; Update Contacts</li>
</ul>
<p>Both LinkedIn and Facebook can get me real and usable contact information. Since the other do not, that&#8217;s why I do not use the other services as a full contact source. This is all dependent on how you interact and want your contacts. If you are restrained on social media, you might be able to add all the individual contacts. The free version of Full Contact limits you to 5000 contacts or less (after they have been deduplicated) so keep that under consideration if you have a larger address book than me.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/zapier-logo-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-94823" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/zapier-logo-1-1.png" alt="zapier-logo" width="500" height="230" /></a></p>
<p>Currently I&#8217;m using Zapier for a single purpose. Zapier automates tasks that you do online. It performs these actions in the background. It is similar to IFTTT, but for the needs relevant in this article Zapier had one function that IFTTT doesn&#8217;t. Zapier has a recipe combination that allows you to save Office 365 contacts to Google Contacts. Since Google is my primary source, I rarely add contacts into Office 365. For the contacts that do get created there, Zapier is happy enough to make sure they get added to Google Contacts silently in the background.</p>
<p><strong>Clean-Up</strong></p>
<p>We have all the data from your contacts in one place. How do we clean them up? Thankfully we can start with de-duplication. There are two different tools we can use for this. The first is Full Contact. Full Contact will churn through and identify duplicate contacts. The web interface will alert you on how many duplicates are found and give you an option to merge them. On the merging screen you can verify that the contacts are related and can be merged together. Once you have done this &#8211; the contacts are merged and you are done.</p>
<p>The second de-duplication you do inside of the Google Contacts. On the left hand side there is a tab that states find duplicates. This will again churn through all your connections and find any remaining duplicates. Google seems to find a handful that Full Contact misses. After running both of these tools though, I haven&#8217;t noticed any blaring duplications.</p>
<p>Here is the pain point for many long time Gmail users. The manual cleanup. I used the web interface, and this took sometime. <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5499575/the-complete-guide-to-fixing-google-contacts">Lifehacker had an old article that documented dumping the contacts to a spreadsheet to clean up your Google contacts</a>. It all depends on how many contacts you have. I removed any contact that did not have either an email address or a phone number. The exception to this is Facebook friends had a reprieve. I assume in some far off day that I&#8217;ll have their contact information to add later. I also fixed any instances where the first and last name were reversed, the first name was an email address, or other blatant issues. I now have a clean contact list.</p>
<p><strong>Backing Up Contacts for Retrieval</strong></p>
<p>While Google isn&#8217;t likely to go away anytime soon, it is good not to rely on it being around forever. Now that everything is merged and clean, it good to do an export now. This allows you to import it into another address book program if Google should ever depart this world.</p>
<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/IFTTT-logo-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-94824" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/IFTTT-logo-1-1.jpg" alt="IFTTT-logo" width="580" height="270" /></a></p>
<p>If you install IFTTT&#8217;s mobile application, you can create rules that will run whenever you add a new contact. The most common use is to dump new contacts into a spreadsheet. Once you set this up, basically you forget about it and it will always run in the background. This will allow you to log all new contacts that come in. Currently I don&#8217;t use this &#8211; but between Full Contact, Google Contacts, and having it locally, I&#8217;m no longer worried about losing my contacts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Apple Customer Service Got It Wrong &#8211; And AT&#038;T Got It Right &#8211; WTF</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2015/10/26/when-apple-customer-service-got-it-wrong-and-att-got-it-right-wtf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=94534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new IPhone is released. A boy has an upgrade on his contract. It is a match made in heaven &#8211; until it isn&#8217;t. Before I start let me give you some back story. I &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/IMG_4445-0-1-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-94533" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/IMG_4445-0-1-874x1024.jpg" alt="IMG_4445-0" width="640" height="750" /></a><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/IMG_4445.jpg" class="broken_link"><br />
</a></p>
<p>A new IPhone is released. A boy has an upgrade on his contract. It is a match made in heaven &#8211; until it isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Before I start let me give you some back story. I am an Apple loyalist &#8211; my Apple Household resume :</p>
<ul>
<li>1 First Gen Mac Mini from 2005 (currently still running and mimicking as an Apple Time Machine on our home network). It is a decade old and still humming along.</li>
<li>2x iPhone 3GS</li>
<li>1x iPhone 4</li>
<li>2x iPhone 4s</li>
<li>2x iPhone 5s</li>
<li>2x iPhone 6s (the story you are about to read)</li>
<li>2x Apple TV (plus 2 more as a gift)</li>
<li>3x iPads (Plus 2 More as a gift)</li>
<li>4-5 iPods of various types</li>
<li>3x MacBook Pros</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are an Android loyalist &#8211; I am deeply entrenched and happy with my platform choice. I don&#8217;t need conversion therapy I used to be a Windows loyalist, but obviously I have since been converted. I still heavily use Windows as part of my employment, it just isn&#8217;t my personal preference. All the equipment above still works (with the exception of 1 broken iPod mini). This is the real reason I stick with Apple, I could burn through a Windows laptop in under a year unless I was buying in the same price range as a Macbook Pro anyways. For my equipment durability there isn&#8217;t much of an Apple tax, I&#8217;m paying for quality over simple hardware specs.</p>
<p>I thought this preamble to the story would be fair. Otherwise most the responses would likely be &#8220;screw apple&#8221;, &#8220;you paid too much&#8221;, or &#8220;you are an idiot&#8221;. Of course, that last one will still likely be the case. I&#8217;m not an Apple apologist. I am just aware what works for me. Now, we can move into the story.</p>
<p>I was excited when the iPhone 6s was announced last month. It wasn&#8217;t any particular spec about the phone I was excited for. My old phone was having issues with volume on phone calls. The last few months I pretty much had to move to speaker phone for my calls. I tried different methods to fix it, but nothing worked. It was working well enough that I was going to wait until my contract was up (October 4th) and just buy the latest version. My life is filled with so many conference calls, a well working phone is extremely important. The other features were just gravy.</p>
<p>I had a business trip on October 6th and would be driving past an Apple Store on the way to the office. I thought this would be the best time to stroll in upgrade my phone and go about my day. I knew which one I wanted, the 6s in Space Grey and a 128GB of space. This in theory should cost me 399 with a two-year contract renewal. It wasn&#8217;t quite that easy though.</p>
<p>I was worried about a couple things though. The first was that most cell phone companies have removed the upgrade phone discount. You now had to finance it through the company at an additional cost. In the past this cost was included in your bill in a way you could not see. This is why cell phone plans have gotten &#8220;cheaper&#8221; recently. Since companies are separating the phone cost from the bill this reduces the amount of the bill by about $20-30.00. You then purchase into one of the 0% financing plans for the hardware. This normally makes the overall bills you pay each month higher than previously. You do have the advantage of yearly upgrades. Apple announced this year that you can finance the phone through them at 0% (with additional charge over the phone price since it includes Apple Care). AT&amp;T and Verizon are the only companies left doing the old upgrade method.</p>
<p>I arrived at the Apple Store at 11AM. One of the greeters had me about 15 minutes before someone could come over and help me. When they came over I gave my specs and said I wanted to use my upgrade. This is where things went wrong. It seems that Apple has stopped accepting the upgrades in the store. He then wanted me to switch plans. I&#8217;m grandfathered into unlimited data and I wasn&#8217;t going to lose that. I also would either have to buy the phone out right (849.00) or use one of the financing plans. He then tried to use the spiel that carriers hide the upgrade cost of the phone into the monthly fee. He said I was a sucker for using the old method and I should change (so he could sell me the phone). I stated that with my upgrade I could get the phone for 399.00 and my monthly fee wouldn&#8217;t change. For both the house iPhones we get unlimited everything for 75.00 &#8211; with the monthly phone fee (if I did financing) it would be higher than it currently is. The salesman said he understood because of the unlimited data and let me on my way. At no point did he concede that even without unlimited data my monthly cost would be cheaper.</p>
<p>I went over the AT&amp;T store. They were helping a couple other people. Once again the salespeople were trying to sell them on a separate phone financing and separate service plan. I rolled my eyes and listened, because I knew I had an upgrade. The sales people made their sale, but said the phone was on backorder. I left without going further.</p>
<p>I went to another mall that was on the way to office. I stopped by the AT&amp;T store at this one. I simply asked if they had phones in stock, they didn&#8217;t. Best Buy mobile was across the way, so I headed over to there. I had to wait again until a salesperson was free, but in the interim they had the phone in stock and set it aside. They originally told they could do the upgrade. When they started entering the information, they said I could not use the reduced cost. The reason was that I had unlimited data. Because of this I had to buy the phone outright and then AT&amp;T takes a portion off of my bill (reverse financing). I said no thank you and moved along. This may have been a good option, but since I never heard of this actually reducing someone&#8217;s monthly bill &#8211; I passed.</p>
<p>Making it into the office after lunch I went to the AT&amp;T website and ordered my phone. I noticed that the total I got was 150.00 more than the upgrade. I was still saving 300.00 so I went and ordered the phone from the website. Once it arrived we realized I ordered it on my wife&#8217;s account. Since she wasn&#8217;t due for an upgrade, this is where the additional cost was from. Now that most carriers are getting rid of subsidized phones, we decided to order her a new one also. This one I managed to get with the right upgrade for 399.00. In the end we managed to get two new phones for 100.00 more than the single phone would have cost me at the Apple Store or Best Buy Mobile.</p>
<p>The real kicker to this story is while I have the corporate discount on my plan &#8211; for being a loyal customer AT&amp;T reduced the data plans by 25% on each line. This makes my monthly unlimited everything plan 68.00. At the end while Apple tried to tell me how much money I would be throwing away, I saved on both phone lines for the monthly cost and a total of 700.00 off the phones. If you have an AT&amp;T upgrade and want a new iPhone, make sure you order it directly through AT&amp;T the first time. This will save you the hassle and run around that I had to deal with.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everyone Likes To Point Out Apple&#8217;s Security Issues &#8211; But What About The Other Guy?</title>
		<link>https://creeva.com/index.php/2013/09/23/everyone-likes-to-point-out-apples-security-issues-but-what-about-the-other-guy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[creeva]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 14:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://creeva.com/?p=93838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; All last week (I&#8217;ll also assume this upcoming week), people have been chiming and laughing over security vulnerabilities in IOS7. The main reason this is in the news is the operating systems has just &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/bth_Apple-logo-1-1.png" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-93839" alt="bth_Apple-logo" src="https://creeva.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/bth_Apple-logo-1-1.png" width="152" height="186" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All last week (I&#8217;ll also assume this upcoming week), people have been chiming and laughing over security vulnerabilities in IOS7. The main reason this is in the news is the operating systems has just been released. They should have also learned from past mistakes.</p>
<p><strong>The &#8220;Big 3&#8221; Issues:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Access to Social Network Information and Data on the Phone</strong> &#8211; This problem is not necessarily a vulnerability. It is a problem of default settings and user awareness. <a href="http://9to5mac.com/2013/02/14/the-ios-6-1-lockscreen-is-again-vulnerable-to-easy-intrusion/">The locked screen issue is something that Apple has been fighting for years</a>. I remember on my 3s the debate of the emergency call button. Back then you could choose the emergency call, go to contacts, and get to the standard IOS system. This is just a repeat, but one that is easy to mitigate. Go to settings -&gt; control center -&gt; set the access on Lock Screen toggle to off. Done. You are no longer vulnerable. In theory with the historical lock screen issues this should have been the default setting.</p>
<p><strong>Thwart the &#8220;Find My Phone&#8221; feature</strong> &#8211; Since you can turn airplane mode on and off within the Control Center, this actually is the same issue as the accessing data. Someone just thought they wanted to seem a little more clever by throwing this highlight in as a second vulnerability. It really isn&#8217;t. You can mitigate this risk the way.</p>
<p><strong>Bypassing the fingerprint reader</strong> <strong>on the 5S</strong> &#8211; Seriously? Who didn&#8217;t think this was going to be compromised? Unfortunately most people don&#8217;t know anyone that could pull this off (<em>I do!</em>). What really is just a security theater performance and response somehow makes it to be big news. It really isn&#8217;t. Biometrics have a long history of being fallible. Since I don&#8217;t have a 5s yet, I don&#8217;t know if you have the option to use a fingerprint and a pin number. If you can, this gives you at least a poor man&#8217;s two factor authentication. This scenario will be significantly more secure than the competitors. If you think someone is going to steal your phone and get your fingerprints to unlock it, use a pin. As an FYI &#8211; they can either lock your phone or plant your prints at a crime scene. Which scenario is more advantageous for them and worse for you?</p>
<p>The main thing about all three of these issues is that they require physical access to your phone. If you have lost physical access to your device and someone else has it &#8211; consider the device already compromised. There are ways to lock the device, but for every method there is some other way to get at the information. The real concern with mobile phones and computers in general are remote exploits. So far nothing on this front has been reported for IOS7.</p>
<p>Because of my friend list, there are two types of people pointing out what amounts to the three issues listed above. The first is IT security professionals. These users are completely expected to point out the flaws. The other type? Most of them are Apple haters who think they have something to chime about. Sadly they seem to ignore their own vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>Android vulnerabilities don&#8217;t get spread around the social network scene for some reason. It&#8217;s not as funny to the apple haters. The Apple users on the other hand, really don&#8217;t care enough to point out that in June <a href="http://www.crn.com/news/security/240156925/samsung-galaxy-s4-contains-serious-smishing-vulnerability-firm-warns.htm">the Galaxy S4 had a remote attack that could cause your phone to send fraudulent text messages</a>. We also don&#8217;t point out <a href="http://www.crn.com/news/security/240149961/android-phone-hack-bypasses-samsung-galaxy-note-2-lock-screen.htm">the Galaxy Note 2 also had a lock screen bypass issue that is the similar to the IOS7 one</a>.</p>
<p>The real problem with Android is how the manufacturers deploy it. Phone makers decide when you get to upgrade your operating system (if at all). <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/19/ios-7-adoption-already-as-high-as-35-in-one-day-apple-and-developers-reap-the-rewards/">In a single day 35% of all IOS devices were upgraded to the latest release</a>. After three days <a href="http://isource.com/2013/09/21/apple-schools-android-50-percent-adoption-rate-for-ios-7-in-3-days/">the adoption rate was 50%</a>. The <a href="http://www.crn.com/news/security/240149961/android-phone-hack-bypasses-samsung-galaxy-note-2-lock-screen.htm">largest threat to any Android is not being upgraded to the latest version</a>. Back <a href="http://9to5google.com/2013/07/08/android-distribution-numbers-updated-for-july-jelly-bean-now-the-most-used-version/">in July 35% of Android devices were still running &#8220;Ginger Bread&#8221;</a>. The problem isn&#8217;t that users don&#8217;t want to upgrade, the companies are just not certifying the latest release for their devices.</p>
<p>Can we all stop with the high and mighty crap? I&#8217;ve given up on the IOS is better than Android for everyone schtick. It isn&#8217;t. It is however better for me. I will defend my usage and post back to the people bragging, yet not understanding the issue. I will also take deserving lumps when I need to.</p>
<p>It is Apple vs. Microsoft all over again. I was a Microsoft defender for years. The thing is, Apple changed. By combining BSD with an Apple UI &#8211; that made the argument swing the other way. Unfortunately the Microsoft users were using the same arguments that no longer applied. OSX is the more powerful system these days (not as power of *nix or pure BSD). For the flexibility &#8211; I moved to a Mac Book Pro for my main machine. I&#8217;ll never look back.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
